<info-registry-entry xmlns="http://info-uri.info/registry" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"  xsi:schemaLocation="http://info-uri.info/registry
C:\herbertv\NISO-id\2004-03-09\info-uri-registry.xsd.xml">
	<info-namespace>lanl-repo</info-namespace>
	<namespace-title>Namespace of identifiers used in the Repository of the LANL Research Library</namespace-title>
	<registration-date>2004-04-05</registration-date>
	<namespace-authority>
		<organisation-name>Los Alamos National Laboratory, Research Library</organisation-name>
		<organisation-address>MS-P362, PO Box 1663, Los Alamos, NM 87545-1362, USA</organisation-address>
		<contact-person>Herbert Van de Sompel</contact-person>
		<contact-email>lww@lanl.gov</contact-email>
		<contact-tel>+1 505 667 4448</contact-tel>
		<contact-uri>http://library.lanl.gov</contact-uri>
	</namespace-authority>
	<identifier-syntax>
<description>Identifiers in the lanl-repo namespace are used to identify information assets
used in the repository of the Research Library of the Los Alamos National
Laboratory.  The syntax is of the form:
info:lanl-repo/_type_/_identifier_
whereby:
&#8729;	_type_ gives an indication of the nature and purpose of the identifier.
Current values for _type_ include 'i' , 'svc' , 'voc' .  Their meaning is
explained in the Namespace Information section.
&#8729;	_identifier_ is a unique string assigned to the information asset.
Examples:
&#8729;	info:lanl-repo/i/000b8c20-51b3-11d8-94f8-e15f3b151c3c
&#8729;	info:lanl-repo/opac/125874
&#8729;	info:lanl-repo/svc/tomods.marc
&#8729;	info:lanl-repo/voc/hasProfile
</description></identifier-syntax>
<identifier-normalization>
<description>All identifiers in the lanl-repo namespace are case-sensitive.</description>
</identifier-normalization>
<namespace-information>
<description>Identifiers in the lanl-repo namespace are used to identify information assets
used in the repository of the Research Library of the Los Alamos National
Laboratory.  Different types of identifiers are used in the repository,
including:
&#8729;	Repository Identifiers: Identifiers assigned by the repository
ingestion process to MPEG-21 DIDL XML wrapper documents that are the unit of
storage in the repository.  These identifiers are also used for the
identification of DIDL Items and DIDL Components (see MPEG-21 DIDL data model)
contained in such XML wrapper documents.  These identifiers are of the form:
info:lanl-repo/i/_identifier_ whereby _identifier_ is a unique string assigned
to an XML wrapper document.  For the identification of DIDL Items and DIDL
Components, fragments are used.
Example: info:lanl-repo/i/000b8c20-51b3-11d8-94f8-e15f3b151c3c .
&#8729;	Content Identifiers: Identifiers that are natively attached to a (set
of) datastream(s) before ingestion into the repository.  They are typically
inherited from the ingested materials, as, in many cases those materials have
identifiers that were attached to them when they were created/published.  These
identifiers are of the form: info:lanl-repo/_namespace_/_identifier_ whereby
_namespace references the namespace from which identifiers were inherited, and
_identifier_ is an identifier in that namespace.
Example: info:lanl-repo/opac/125874
&#8729;	ServiceType identifiers: Identifiers accorded to services that can be
applied to repository content.  These identifiers are of the form
info:lanl-repo/svc/_identifier_ whereby _identifier_ is a unique string
acorded to a specific service.  Example: info:lanl-repo/svc/tomods.marc.
&#8729;	Identifiers for vocabulary terms: Identifiers used to represent
properties of assets stored in the repository, or relationships between such
assets.  These identifiers are used in RDF statements.  These identifiers are
of the form info:lanl-repo/voc/_identifier_ whereby _identifier_ is a unique
string acorded to a property or type of relationship.
Example: info:lanl-repo/voc/hasProfile .</description>
</namespace-information>
</info-registry-entry>
